The story of an ordinary woman in an extraordinary time.
Charlotte Gray is a drama, history, romance film directed by Gillian Armstrong.
This is a drama set in Nazi-occupied France at the height of World War II.
Charlotte Gray tells the compelling story of a young Scottish woman working with the
French Resistance in the hope of rescuing her lover, a missing RAF pilot.
Based on the best-selling novel by Sebastian Faulks.
Charlotte Gray, played by Cate Blanchett.
Julien Levade, played by Billy Crudup.
Levade, played by Michael Gambon.
Peter Gregory, played by Rupert Penry-Jones.
Renech, played by Anton Lesser.
Richard Cannerly, played by James Fleet.
Charlotte Gray is a 2001 romance war drama film directed by Gillian Armstrong.
The screenplay was adapted from Sebastian Faulks' 1999 novel Charlotte Gray.
It is set in Vichy France during World War II.
The film stars Cate Blanchett, James Fleet, Abigail Cruttenden,
Rupert Penry-Jones, Michael Gambon and Billy Crudup.
The story is based on the exploits of women in Britain's Special Operations Executive
(SOE) who worked with the French resistance in Nazi-occupied France.
The film explores themes of france, nazi, escape, loss of loved one, resistance.
The tone is emotional.